lan Adams

User Experience Designer

Chicago, Illinois

www.ianadamsdesign.com ianfranceadams@gmail.com 828.699.4071

Summary

Meticulous yet imaginative user-centered designer with experience in transportation and customer service. Especially drawn to the research and prototyping phases of the design process and interested in challenges within a range of products and industries.

Tools

Work Experience

UX/UI Designer VeoRide - Chicago, Illinois August 2018 - July 2019

> Revamped dockless micro-mobility share company's mobile app while applying the user-centered design process to continuously, incrementally improve the product experience for all involved

- Released new, streamlined app with fresh aesthetics (in collaboration with graphic designer) and improved usability in January 2019. Produced final UI designs using Sketch and Zeplin
- Conducted regular user research initiatives, translating findings into concrete app and operations improvement recommendations
- i Created brand new internal app to help with field operations efficiency, work documentation, and accountability

Full-Service Shopper and Delivery Driver

Instacart - Chicago, Illinois

February 2017 - August 2018

Worked independently with sophisticated mobile technology to resolve problems swiftly and provide high levels of customer service

Regional Tanker Driver (CDL)

Schneider Bulk Carriers - Gary, Indiana

October 2015 - January 2017

Interacted safely and professionally with tractor-trailer and tanker equipment, delivering chemicals in industrial settings and using in-truck satellite technology to effectively communicate daily with dispatch

Skills

User Stories Sketch User Flows Adobe XD Prototyping Zeplin LoFi/HiFi Wireframing Jira User Interface Design InVision Branding Balsamiq Visual Design UsabilityHub Sketching Optimal Workshop

User Research Figma Design Thinking Illustrator Competitive Analysis Photoshop Omnigraffle Personas A/B Testing HTML/CSS User Testing JavaScript (basic)

Writing Git/Github

Education

Bloc Designer Track

Immersive, mentor-led apprenticeship in UX/UI Design Bloc.io, 2017-2018

Bachelor of Arts in Music

University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, 2012

Undergraduate Study in Guitar Performance

University of North Carolina School of the Arts Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 2007 - 2009

Other Interests

Backpacking Hiking Camping Biking Traveling Geography Photography Art Classical Music American Music History Economics/Finance Health/Nutrition Permaculture Philosophy Religion German Japanese Culture Kendo Meditation Rinzai Zen Buddhism